Bart Bok collection, 1928-1983
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series 5: Instruction Files, 1936-1974, 1.26 linear feet (Approximately 2,520 items)
  - Astronomy 212, Interstellar Absorption and Dark Nebulae. 1954 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Astronomy 241, Topics in Radio Astronomy. 1953-1954 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Astronomy 310, Galactic Structure and Dynamics. 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Astronomy S2. 1971-1974 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Kinematics and Dynamics of Our Galaxy, Summer Institute for Astronomy and Astrophysics-Ten Lectures. 1968 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - One-Semester Beginning Course in Astronomy-Outline. 1971 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Stellar Statistics-Seminar. 1936 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Structure of the Milky Way, Series of Fourteen Seminars- Notes. 1952 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Structure of the Milky Way, Harvard-Seminar. 1952 (Box 29, Folder 2)
- Series 6: Publication Files, 1928-1983, 1.16 linear feet (Approximately 2,320 items)
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. Publication Files document Dr. Bok's research and writing career. It contains publications on galactic structure and dynamics, stellar and interstellar matter, the Milky Way, Dark Nebulae, Star Formation, Spiral Structure of the Galaxy, and Star Clouds of Magellan.
  - General. 1928 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - General. 1931 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - General. 1934 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - General. 1935 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - General. 1936 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - General. 1937 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - General. 1938 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - General. 1939 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - General. 1941 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - General. 1942 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - General. 1944 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - General. 1945 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - General. 1946 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - General. 1947 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - General. 1948 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - General. 1949 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - General. 1951 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - General. 1952 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - General. 1953 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - General. 1954 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - General. 1955 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - General. 1956 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - General. 1957 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - General. 1958 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - General. 1959 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - General. 1960 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - General. 1961 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - General. 1962 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - General. 1963 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - General. 1964 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - General. 1965 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - General. 1966 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - General. 1967 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - General. 1968 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - General. 1969 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - General. 1970 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - General. 1971 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - General. 1972 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - General. 1973 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - General. 1974 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - General. 1975 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - General. 1976 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - General. 1977 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - General. 1978 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - General. 1979 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - General. 1981 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - General. 1982 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - General. 1983 (Box 32, Folder 3)
- Series 7: Subject Files, 1968-1982, .21 linear feet (Approximately 420 items)
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. Subject Files consist of material relating to Bart Bok's personal and professional interests. Including special events, the Bok Fellowship, Bok Prize student awards, travel-related information and subjects related to international developments in astronomy.
  - Astronomy in Iraq. 1982 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Astronomy in Mexico. 1978-1979 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Bok Fellowship. 1973-1982 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Bok Prize. 1974-1980 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Kitt Peak 90-inch Telescope Dedication Events. 1968 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Pulsars. 1968-1969 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Retirement. 1974 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Siding Spring Observatory. 1965 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Travel-Australia/Hawaii. 1977-1978 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Travel-General. 1979 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Travel-India. 1977-1980 (Box 32, Folder 14)
- Series 8: Photographs, 1933-1982, 3.76 linear feet (Approximately 7,520 items)
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series is divided into five subseries: Stellar Objects (1950-1982), Facilities and Equipment (1933-1980), General (1944-1979), Negatives and Slides (1951-1980) and Oversize (1971-1978). Stellar Objects includes images of stellar and interstellar matter and photographic charts. Facilities and Equipment documents the construction of various international observatories and the installation of astronomical equipment, with a particular emphasis on radio telescopes. Photographs of Dr. Bok's visits to international observatories are also included. General includes Dr. Bok's personal images of himself, family members, notable astronomers and colleagues, the special events such as the Bok Symposium and his retirement luncheon. Negatives and Slides include images of stellar and interstellar matter, facilities and equipment. Also includes personal and professional images. Oversize includes photographic charts and diagrams of stellar and interstellar objects and matter and images of facilities and equipment.
  - Subseries: Stellar Objects, 1950-1982
    - Barnard 68 and 72. 1980 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Barnard 335. undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Bok Globule in Coalsack. 1977 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Coalsack Globule 2. undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Clusters. undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Comet Bennett. 1970 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - General. 1950-1980 (Box 33, Folder 7-8)
    - General. 1951-1970 (Box 33, Folder 9-10)
    - General. 1974-1977 (Box 33, Folder 11-12)
    - General. undated (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - General Charts-Publications. undated (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Globules. 1980 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Keyhole Nebula (eta carinae). 1978 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Magellanic Clouds. 1979 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Milky Way by Lund Observatory. 1981-1982 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Orion Nebula (Horsehead Nebula). 1964-1979 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Priscilla Bok Lunar Crater. 1979 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Southern Coalsack. undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Southern Milky Way in H [as proportional to] light. 1952-1953 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Stromlo Atlas (composite). undated (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Trifid Nebula. 1978 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Vela Pulsar. undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Subseries: Facilities and Equipment, 1933-1980
    - Agassiz Radio Telescope. 1956 (Box 34, Folder 12-13)
    - Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory, Puerto Rico. 1967 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Array. undated (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - General. 1933-1979 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - General. 1936-1978 (Box 34, Folder 17-18)
    - Kitt Peak, Tucson, Arizona. 1959-1980 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Perth Observatory, Australia. 1974-1978 (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Radio Telescopes-Various. 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Siding Spring Observatory, Australia. 1972 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Siding Spring Observatory, Australia. 1972 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Steward Observatory. 1967-1968 (Box 35, Folder 3-4)
  - Subseries: General, 1944-1979
    - Bok, Bart. 1951-1979 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Bok, Priscilla. 1966-1974 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Bok Symposium, University of Arizona. 1970 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - International Astronomical Union Symposium, Bondi, Australia. 1963 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Personal. 1945-1966 (Box 35, Folder 9-11)
    - Professional. 1944-1974 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Professional. 1944-1974 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Retirement Luncheon. 1974 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Subseries: Negatives and Slides, 1951-1980
    - Barnard 361. 1969 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Bok, Bart. 1969 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Bok, Priscilla. 1979 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Facilities and Equipment-General. 1977 (Box 36, Folder 6-7)
    - Kitt Peak. undated (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Personal. 1959 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Stellar Objects-General. 1951-1980 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Subseries: Oversize, 1971-1978
    - Charts and Diagrams. undated (Box 37, Folder 1-5)
    - Charts and Diagrams. 1971-1978 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Cocoparra Range. 1958 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Facilities and Equipment. 1968-1979 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Magellanic Cloud Charts. undated (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Stellar Objects. undated (Box 38, Folder 4-6)
    - Stellar Objects-Negatives. undated (Box 38, Folder 7)